Welcome to our video tutorial on seller-fulfilled prime, also known as SFP.
In this introductory video, we will go over program specific details, including eligibility requirements.
One of the key benefits for SFP sellers is getting prime branding on eligible offers, while fulfilling
orders directly from their own warehouse.
Sellers will ship orders same day with free one and two-day shipping to Amazon Prime customers.
When you enroll products in seller-fulfilled prime, the prime badge will be added next to your products
in the Amazon store.
This makes your products more discoverable, and prime customers know that you're able to offer fast,
reliable delivery and excellent customer service.
In order to enroll products in seller-fulfilled prime, you need to meet the following pre-qualification
criteria.
If you meet these requirements, you're able to start your seller-fulfilled prime trial.
First, the default shipping address connected to your selling account must be a domestic U.
S.
shipping address.
Second, you need to have a professional selling account.
Third, you need to have fulfilled 100 orders and meet the shipping performance bar over the past
90 days.
Specifically, that means that your cancellation rate can't be higher than 2.5%.
Your valid tracking rate needs to be greater than 95%, and your late shipment rate is less than
4%.
You can find these metrics in your account health dashboard.
You can access the dashboard by clicking on the Seller Central Main Menu.
Go to Performance and click on Account Health.
Your shipping performance metrics are then displayed in the far right column.
Please note that the pre-qualification requirements that allow you to enroll in the trial are different
from the requirements during the actual trial period.
You're ready to enroll in the Seller-fulfilled prime trial.
First, navigate to sellercentral.
amazon.
com/seller-fulfilled-prime/register/welcome.
If you meet all pre-qualification requirements, you'll be able to enroll in the trial by entering
your account information.
This includes your company's name, your phone number, and your email address.
You'll also need to choose your primary warehouse address.
In order to be eligible for the Seller-fulfilled prime trial, remember that your warehouse address
needs to have a domestic U.
S.
shipping address.
After you have entered the information, click Save Changes.
On the next page, agree to program policies and proceed.
After you've successfully registered for the trial, make sure to continue watching our video
on the requirements during the Seller-fulfilled prime trial period.
Thank you, and happy selling in the Amazon store.